Jez Williams

Freelance Front end developer

07825778919 jezfx.com jez@jezfx.com

About

Since graduating in computer science six years ago, I've found love in the creative side of the web. I've been freelancing for three years and enjoy being in new environments and learning new skills. Most recently, I've been building with React and progressing deeper into backend development to compliment my frontend skills.

Experience

Twine.fm / Front end, React

MAR 2017 - PRESENT, MANCHESTER

Twine are in the process of moving their current application over to ReactJS and my role in this transition has been building components, working with Redux and adding animations and transitions throughout the site.

Vossier.com / Front end, React

FEB 2017 - MAR 2017, REMOTE

The development for the redesign of http://vossier.com for a collaboration they did with Opera on ProductHunt. Built in React, and Prismic.io a headless Javascript CMS.

Ampersand x2 / Front end

AUG 2016 - DEC 2016 / SEP 2015 - DEC 2015, MANCHESTER

Front end development using Magento 2 for <u>Web-blinds</u> and <u>Regatta</u>. Using; React, Backbone and ITCSS for the frontend architecture.

Mission Mars / Wordpress Developer

FEB 2016 - AUG 2016, MANCHESTER

As their only digital resource my main accomplishment was the development of a large WP parent theme which is used as a child theme for all their bars, clubs and venues around the UK.

Formisimo / Design & Front end

JAN 2016 - FEB 2016, MANCHESTER

Contacted to re-brand, design and build their client facing site. Full project breakdown: jezfx.com/work/formisimo

Havas / Wordpress Development

NOV 2015 - DEC 2015, MANCHESTER

Contract was to build an in-house pharmaceutical wordpress site.

Source[Lab] / Front end

MAR 2015 - SEP 2015, MANCHESTER

Contacted as a designer front end developer working alongside two other backend developers in a Rails environment.

Telcom / Design

AUG 2015 - OCT 2015, MANCHESTER

Working with the marketing department on their latest campaigns designing packaging and posters.

Fatsoma / Wordpress Developer

MAY 2013 - NOV 2014, MANCHESTER

I built a wordpress platform to allow the sales team to quickly spin up and launch WP sites for clients for clients.

Envirofone / Design & Front end

SEP 2011 - FEB 2013, MACCLESFIELD

Worked on the main envirofone.com site and as our own client we were able to make very methodical data driven decisions.

Education

Staffordshire University / 2:1 BSc Computing Science

2007 - 2011, STAFFORDSHIRE

I was able to cover a wide range of programing languages and programming concepts. My final year project was a sass product for creatives which collected media content from their various online services to generate an online portfolio.

Mid Cheshire College / Distinction, Music Technology

2005 - 2007, NORTHWICH

I first developed my interest in computers and technology while producing music in studios which I went on to pursue in Uni.

Volunteer Experience

I enjoy volunteering at various meetups and conferences.

Web Summit

2016, LISBON

Smashing Conf

2015, OXFORD

DNX

2015, BERLIN

LeanConf

2014, MANCHESTER